Thread Waxing Space (Gallery)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Thread Waxing Space records
1980s-2001
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Thread Waxing Space
36.7 linear feet
The records of the New York City gallery Thread Waxing Space measure 36.7 linear feet and date from 1980s-2001 (bulk 1991-2001). Exhibitions and events held at the gallery are documented through correspondence, artists' bios, printed materials, shipping records, photographic materials, audiovisual materials, scattered electronic records, and other administrative records. Also found are a handful of artist research files, clippings, and press books.
Provenance
The Thread Waxing Space records were donated in 2008 by Thread Waxing Space founder Tim Nye.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings and electronic records with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Historical Note
Founded by Tim Nye, Thread Waxing Space opened in September 1991 on the second floor of 476 Broadway in New York City. Named after the building's previous occupants -- a factory which produced waxed thread -- the non-profit gallery and performance space explored the interdisciplinary nature of the arts and expanded the boundaries of a traditional gallery through diverse programming.
Thread Waxing Space had multiple exhibition spaces, including the main gallery where the gallery's curators and independent curators organized solo and group exhibitions of contemporary artists working in all types of mediums; the Project Room, a space typically showing works of emerging or under-represented artists; and the Kitchenette, showing works by video artists. In addition to solo and group exhibitions, dance performances, readings, musical events, film screening, lectures, discussion panels, benefits, and arts education programs for students were all frequently held at Thread Waxing Space.
Exhibitions in the main gallery and the Project Room typically ran concurrently for 4-6 weeks. One of the more prominent exhibits held at Thread Waxing Space was "Beck & Al Hansen: Playing With Matches," an exhibit of artworks by musician and songwriter Beck and his grandfather, Fluxus artist Al Hansen. Other artists with solo exhibitions at Thread Waxing Space include Leonardo Drew and Virgil Marti. Thread Waxing Space closed in 2001.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the New York City gallery Thread Waxing Space measure 36.7 linear feet and date from 1980s-2001 (bulk 1991-2001). Exhibitions and events held at the gallery are documented through correspondence, artists' bios, printed materials, shipping records, photographic materials, audiovisual materials, scattered electronic records, and other administrative records. Also found are a handful of artist research files, clippings, and press books.
Program Files provide a nearly comprehensive documentation of the exhibitions, performances, lectures and other programs held at Thread Waxing Space. Materials include correspondence, contracts, administrative records, printed materials, photographic materials, audiovisual materials, and scattered electronic records.
Research Files include a handful of folders containing materials related to artists, such as resumes, biographies, printed materials, clippings, and scattered correspondence. Press books containing photocopied newspaper and magazine articles, scattered clippings and scattered printed materials are found in Press Files. Audiovisual Materials contain sound and video recordings presumably of artists found in the Program Files series.
Exhibitions and performances for which there is considerable documentation in the collection include Post-IZUM Moods Music Series (1993), "Don't Look Now" (1994) curated by Joshua Decter, "Garbage!" (1995), "Beyond Ars Medica: Treasures from the Mutter Museum" (1995-1996), "European Comics: Another Image" (1997), "Celluloid Cave" (1997), "Ascent of Western Civilization: American Independent Rock, 1976-1991" (1997), "Jump Cut (Faust)" (1997), "Sanctuary: A Spiritual Music Festival" (1998), "Conceptual Art as Neurobiological Praxis" (1999), "Foul Play" (1999), and "Mr. Fascination" (1999-2000); and traveling exhibitions "Archigram: Experimental Architecture 1961-1974" (1998-1999), "Spectacular Optical" (1998-1999), "After the Gold Rush" (1999), and "Achieving Failure: Gym Culture 2000" (2000).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 4 series:
Series 1: Program Files, 1980s-2001 (Boxes 1-38; 35.7 linear feet)
Series 2: Research Files, 1993-2000 (Box 35; 8 folders)
Series 3: Press Files, 1991-circa 2001 (Boxes 35, 38; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 4: Audiovisual Materials, 1989-1993, undated (Boxes 35-36; 0.6 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Art galleries, Commercial -- New York (State) -- New York; Art -- Study and teaching -- New York (State) -- New York; Performance art -- New York (State) -- New York
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Video recordings
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Program Files, 1980s-2001, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-38; 35.7 linear feet)
  Program Files provide a nearly comprehensive documentation of exhibitions, performances, lectures, and other events held by Thread Waxing Space. Materials found include correspondence with curators, artists and arts organizations; shipping records; contracts; insurance records; slides and photographs of installations, artwork, and events; clippings; catalogs, cards, and invitations; posters and flyers; and scattered electronic records. This series contains sound and video recordings of performances and exhibitions, the bulk of which are unique recordings. Additional audiovisual recordings are found in Series 4.
  Folders are arranged chronologically by exhibition date.
  - Paul Pagk (Sept. 19 - Nov. 2, 1991), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Yau and Raphael Rubinstein, "Reading" (Oct. 9, 1991), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hyun Soo Choi, "Seven large-scale paintings" (Nov. 7 - Dec. 21, 1991), 1990-1992, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - "Sculpture: Leonardo Drew, Lisa Hoke, and Brad Kahlhamer" (Jan. 16 - Feb. 28, 1992), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Green Card Writers (Feb. 14, 1992), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chris Martin, "There Is No Inside, There Is No Outside"(Mar. 13, 1992), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Behind Bars," Curated by Meg O'Rourke (Mar. 17 - Apr. 25, 1992), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Larry Litt, "Humorology" (Apr. 3 and 10, 1992), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "The Banquet," Organized by Hunter Reynolds and Chrysanne Stathacos (May 1-23, 1992), 1992, 1995, (2 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - "Mssr. B's Curio Shop," Organized by Saul Ostrow (June 6 - July 11, 1992), 1991-1993, (5 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 1, Folder 12-16)
  - "Miauhaus," Organized by Gottfried Tollmann (July 20 - Aug. 8, 1992), 1991-1993, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
  - Front 242, "Art & Strategy" (Aug. 12 - Sept. 1, 1992), 1992, (2 folders; includes 2 sound discs: CD) (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - "The Interactive Show," Curated by Neil Zusman and Carol Parkinson (Sept. 10 - Oct. 10, 1992), 1989, 1991-1992, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
  - Amanda Weil, "Glass Photographs Office Installation" (Sept. 10 - [Nov. 3?], 1992), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Taylor Mead and William Rand Reading (Oct. 14, [1992]), 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Techstasy: The Body and Technology" (Oct. 15 - Nov. 4, 1992), 1992-1993, (3 folders; includes 2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Leonardo Drew (Nov. 7 - Dec. 12, 1992), 1992-1993, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - "Supermodernism," Panels Organized by Robert C. Morgan (Nov. 12, 19, Dec. 3, 10, 1992), 1992, (2 folders; includes 3 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - "I Am the Enunciator," Curated by Christian Leigh (Jan. 9 - Feb. 20, 1993), 1992-1993, (8 folders; includes 1 sound disc: CD, 2 videocassettes: VHS, and 1 computer disc: 3.5") (Box 2, Folder 10-17)
  - "I Am the Enunciator," Curated by Christian Leigh (Jan. 9 - Feb. 20, 1993), 1992-1993, (Includes 2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Paul Pagk (Mar. 5 - Apr. 17, 1993), 1993, (2 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - King Forward and Big Funk Performance (Mar. 6, 19, 1993), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jessie Allen, "Reason Cannot Reach It: Seeking New Ways to Talk About Race" (Mar. 18, 1993), 1993, (2 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Marc Straus and Heather McHugh Poetry Reading (Apr. 16, 1993), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Triangle Artists' Workshop Panel Discussion (Apr. 21, 27, 1993), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "From Terrain Vague to the Hummingbird's Chest," Curated by Sussan Deihim (Apr. 23 - May 7, 1993), 1991-1993, (7 folders; includes 2 sound discs: CD, 3 videocassettes: VHS, and 2 sound cassettes) (Box 3, Folder 9-15)
  - Hyun Soo Choi (May 12 - June 26, 1993), 1991-1993, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Pico Harden (May 12 - June 26, 1993), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Forging Ground: Symposium on Engaging the Public and Rethinking Exhibition Approaches" (May 25 and June 3, 1993), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mr. Jed, "His Puppet Touched Me" (June 5-6, 1993), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Blue Man Group Benefit (July 12, 1993), 1993, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - "Gone Beyond Gone," Curated by Dominique Nahas (Sept. 18 - Oct. 23, 1993), 1981, 1986-1993, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - "(oh, shyness)," Organized by Luca Buvoli (Sept. 25 - Oct. 23, 1993), 1993, (2 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - "Writers Read," Organized by John Reed (Oct. 7, 1993), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Steve Lacy and Alain Kirili Performance (Oct. 27, 1993), 1992-1993, 1996, (2 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Post-IZUM Moods Music Series (Oct. 31 - Nov. 14, 1993) (Box 4)
    - General, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Budget Info, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Contracts, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Art Exhibition, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Final Report, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Post-IZUM Moods Music Series (Oct. 31 - Nov. 14, 1993) (Box 5)
    - Final Report, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Income, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Fode Kouyate (Oct. 31, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Houria Aichi (Nov. 2-3, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - MCO Composer Evan Lurie (Nov. 4, 6, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - MCO Director Richard Clark (Nov. 4, 6, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - MCO Composer Ben Neill (Nov. 4, 6, 1993), 1992-1993, (Includes 1 sound disc: CD) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - MCO Composer Pauline Oliveros (Nov. 4, 6, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - MCO Composer Ruth Schonthal (Nov. 4, 6, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - MCO Composer David Soldier (Nov. 4, 6, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - MCO Composer John Zorn (Nov. 4, 6, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Alberto Neuman (Nov. 5, 7, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Solo Instruments (Nov. 9-10, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "1001 Sounds" Instrumentals, David Behrman and James Lo (Nov. 10, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "1001 Sounds" Installation/Performance, Ken Butler (Nov. 9, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "1001 Sounds" Solo Instrumental/Installation, Cooper-Moore (Nov. 9, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "1001 Sounds" Installation/Solo Performance, Michael De Lia (Nov. 9, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "1001 Sounds" Solo Performance, Reza Derakshani (Nov. 10, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "1001 Sounds" Solo Performance, Zusaan Kali Fasteau (Nov. 9, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "1001 Sounds" Solo Instrumental, Hassan Hakmoun (Nov. 9, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "1001 Sounds" Solo Instrumental, Tom Hamilton (Nov. 9, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "1001 Sounds" Solo Instrumental/Installation, Steve Marsh (Nov. 10, 1993), 1993, (Includes 1 sound cassette) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "1001 Sounds" Installation/Performance, Elliot Sharp (Nov. 10, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "1001 Sounds" Installation/Solo Performance, Carol Szymanski and Ben Neill (Nov. 10, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Henry Threadgill (Nov. 11-12, 1993), 1993, (Includes 2 sound cassettes: DAT) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Alternative Rock, Etc. (Nov. 13-14, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Lawrence D. "Butch" Morris (Nov. 11-12, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Installation Designer, Thomas Leeser, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Installation, Tom O'Horgan, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Installation, Kevin N. Hylton, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Installation, Roy Crosse, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - "1001 Sounds" Solo Inst./Install., Jamey Haddad and Todd Isler (Nov. 10, 1993), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Installation, Skip La Plante, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Installation, Peter Whitney, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Installation, Christian Marclay - VOID, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - [Susan James] Notes, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Technical, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Grants FY93-94, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Contact Lists, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Budget, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Mailer and Program, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Installation Artists and Notes, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Artist Contracts, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Publicity, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Tickets, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Travel and Accomodations, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Meeting Minutes and Related, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Photographic Materials, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Post-IZUM Moods Music Series (Oct. 31 - Nov. 14, 1993) (Box 6)
    - Photographic Materials, 1993, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - Video Recordings - Dubs, 1993, (4 folders; 10 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 6, Folder 4-7)
    - Video Recordings, 1993, (12 videocassettes: Hi8 housed in Box 36, Shoebox 1) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Video Recordings, 1993, (19 videocassettes: Hi8 housed in Box 36, Shoebox 2) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Sound Recordings, 1993, (1 sound disc: DAT, and 1 sound cassette) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Siobhan Liddell (Nov. 20 - Dec. 23, 1993), 1993-1995, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - Robert Tannen (Nov. 20 - Dec. 23, 1993), 1990, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Alternative Music (Jan. 7-8, 1994), 1993-1994, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - "Don't Look Now" (Jan. 22 - Feb. 26, 1994) curated by Joshua Decter, 1993-1994, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
  - "Don't Look Now" (Jan. 22 - Feb. 26, 1994)curated by Joshua Decter, 1993-1994, (5 folders; includes 1 videocassette: Hi8, and 2 computer discs: 3.5") (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Meghan Boody, "Play Dead Dead Play" (Jan. 22 - Feb.26, 1994), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Kitchenette (Feb. 4-25, 1994), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Leonardo Drew (Mar. 12 - Apr. 23, 1994), 1994, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 8-11)
  - Art New York International [Art Fair] (Apr. 28 - May 1, 1994), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - April/May Music Series (Apr. 29-30, May 6-9, 1994), 1994-1995, (6 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS tape, and 1 sound disc: CD) (Box 7, Folder 13-18)
  - April/May Music Series (Apr. 29-30, May 6-9, 1994), 1994-1995, (4 folders; includes 3 videocassettes: VHS tape) (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
  - "Written/Spoken/Drawn in lacanian ink" (May 3-7, 1994), 1993-1994, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - Nayland Blake, "The Philosopher's Suite" (May 17 - June 11, 1994), 1991-1994, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 7-10)
  - Ellen Driscoll and Nene Humphrey (May 14 - June 11, 1994), 1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - June Music Series (June 15-26, 1994), 1994-1995, (5 folders) (Box 8, Folder 12-16)
  - June Music Series (June 15-26, 1994), 1994-1995, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - June Music Series, Commercial Sound Recordings (June 15-26, 1994), 1994, (1 sound disc box set: 2 CDs, and 1 sound cassette) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - June Music Series, Video Recordings (June 15-26, 1994), 1994, (5 folders; 13 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 9, Folder 4-8)
  - "Crash," Curated by Robert Reynolds and Thomas Zummer (July 7 - Aug. 15, 1994), 1994, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 9-13)
  - "Paul and Paik" at The Kitchen Video Annex (July 7 - Aug. 15, 1994), 1994 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "Shut Up! Little Man," Directed by Gregg Gibbs (Sept. 8-11, 15-18, 1994), 1994, (3 folders; includes 2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Timothy Leary, "How to Operate Your Brain" (Sept. 22, 1994), 1994 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pieter Schoolwerth, "Astrid's Secret Banana" (Sept. 29 - Oct. 29, 1994), 1994, (3 folders; includes 4 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
  - Charles Spurrier (Sept. 29 - Oct. 29, 1994), 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Larry Litt, "Video Golem" (Oct. 1, 1994), 1994, (Includes 1 sound cassette) (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - io Literary Magazine Benefit (Nov. 7, 1994), 1994 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Violence and Women: Artists Speak on the Visual Language of Survival" (Nov. 8, 1994), 1993-1995, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
  - "Logo Non Logo," Curated by Robert C. Morgan (Nov. 17 - Dec. 23, 1994), 1982, 1991-1996, (5 folders) (Box 10, Folder 13-17)
  - "Logo Non Logo," Curated by Robert C. Morgan (Nov. 17 - Dec. 23, 1994), 1982, 1991-1996, (10 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-10)
  - Brad Kahlhamer (Nov. 17 - Dec. 23, 1994), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Managing Morality Symposium" Benefit for Bill T. Jones (Nov. 28, 1994), 1992-1995 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Marc Strauss Poetry Reading, "One Word" (Dec. 1, 1994), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Karen Finley, "A Certain Level of Denial" (Jan. 6-8, 1995), 1995 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - AmFAR Benefit Exhibition (Jan. 12 - Feb. 11, 1995), 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Peggy Preheim (Jan. 13 - Feb. 11, 1995), 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Ellen Driscoll, "Passionate Attitudes" (Feb. 23 - Apr. 8, 1995), 1991-1995, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
  - "Garbage!," Curated by Ellen F. Salpeter and Anne R. Pasternak, General, (Feb. 23 - Apr. 8, 1995), 1994-1995, (2 folders; includes 1 computer disc: 3.5") (Box 11, Folder 19-20)
  - "Garbage!," Curated by Ellen F. Salpeter and Anne R. Pasternak (Feb. 23 - Apr. 8, 1995) (Box 12)
    - Othello Anderson and Fern Shaffer, 1990-1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Arman, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Art Club 2000, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Gary Bachman, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Betty Beaumont, 1989-1995 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Ashley Bickerton, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Bob Braine, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Michael Bulka, circa 1995 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Mel Chin, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Meg Cranston, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Jay Critchley, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Bob Braine, Mark Dion and Alexis Rockman, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Mark Dion, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Nancy Dwyer, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - John Feckner, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Sophie Fenwick, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Rainer Ganahl, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Karin Giusti, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Hans Haacke, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Peter Hopkins, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Ronald Jones, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Allan Kaprow, circa 1995 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Richard Kostelanetz, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Vik Muniz, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Lois Nesbitt, 1992-1995 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Dan Peterman, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Claes Oldenburg, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Tim Rollins, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Stephania Serena, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Daniel Spoerri, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Rikrit Tirvanija, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Mierle Laderman Ukeles, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Ajencia de Viaje, 1992-1995 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Meyer Vaisman, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Andy Warhol, circa 1995 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Krzysztof Wodiczko, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Video Recording, 1995, (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Joseph Beuys Films (Apr. 5-8, 1995), 1991-1995 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Urban Bush Women Dance Residency (Apr. 12-22, 1995), 1994-1995, (2 folders; includes 2 sound cassettes) (Box 12, Folder 39-40)
  - "Unglued" (Apr. 26-27, 1995), 1995 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - "Murder," Curated by John Yau (May 4 - June 10, 1995), 1992-1995, (5 folders; includes 2 sound cassettes) (Box 12, Folder 42-46)
  - Kathleen Kucka (May 4 - June 10, 1995), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - NAAO Panel, "Artists and Attitude (on Art)" (May 19, 1995), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - ST-X Music Performance (May 25, 1995), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Ken Butler (June 20 - July 7, 1995), 1995, (2 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
  - Sue Rees and Jonathan Bepler, "Automation of Accidental Gestures" (July 12-28, 1995), 1994-1995, (3 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS, and 1 sound cassette) (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
  - "Unglued" (Sept. 5-9, 1995), 1995, (2 folders; includes 1 sound cassette, and 2 sound cassettes: DAT) (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
  - Karen Finley (Sept. 5-8, 1995), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Sussan Deyhim, "Vocodeliks" (Sept. 6, 1995), 1995, (2 videocassettes: VHS and Hi8) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - "Art Matters" Launch Party (Sept. 10-11, 1995), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - James Elaine, "Objects From The Dying Salon" (Sept. 30 - Nov. 9, 1995), 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Stefan Roloff, "Pence Springs Resort" (Sept. 30 - Nov. 9, 1995), 1992-1997, (6 folders) (Box 13, Folder 15-20)
  - Darrin Martin, "Ceilings Without Walls" (Kitchenette) (Sept. 30 - Nov. 9, 1995), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Laurie Shapiro, World Art Benefit (Oct. 6, 1995), 1995 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "The NEA Tapes," Soho Arts Festival (Oct. 6-8, 1995), 1995 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "The Usual Suspects" Bomb Benefit (Oct. 7, 1995), 1995 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Susan Tunick, Lecture: The History of Terra Cotta Buildings in Greenwich Village (Oct. 26, 1995), 1995 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Artist-Voter (Nov. 4, 1995), 1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Hiroshi Sunairi, Jackie O'Neill, and Alex Bag, "Famous in New York" (Nov. 15, 1995), 1995, (2 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
  - Skowhegan Panel, "Digital Directions: New Art or New Packaging?" (Nov. 16, 1995), 1995 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "Beyond Ars Medica: Treasures from the Mutter Museum" (Nov. 19, 1995 - Jan. 11, 1996) (Box 14)
    - Max Aguilera-Hellweg, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Gwen Atkin/Allan Ludwig, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Steven Katzman, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Scott Lindgren, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Olivia Parker, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Arne Svenson, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Joel-Peter Witkin, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Pedestals/Vitrines, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Rosamund Purcell, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - List of Artists, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Support Material, 1994-1996, (Oversized materials housed in Box 38, Folder 1) (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Press, 1995-1996, (2 folders; oversized materials housed in Box 38, Folder 2) (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
    - Grey Art Gallery NYU, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Dia Vitrines, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Wall Paint and Pedestal Paint, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Ralph Rugoff Essay, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Barbara Marie Stafford Essay, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Attendance, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Loan Agreements, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Shelby Lee Adams, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 29)